(
"ai_sub_version": "1.12.0",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 3,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-pro-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600,
"overwrite_system_prompt": false
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"encoder": "h264_qsv"
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 1,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
新衣装お披露目＆超告知あり!?
New Outfit Reveal & Super Announcement!?
Sakura Miko Birthday Live 2026: Fashion Beat
さくらみこ
Sakura Miko
3/5 さくらみこ
3/5 Sakura Miko
常闇トワ / 大空スバル
Tokoyami Towa / Oozora Subaru
白上フブキ / 大神ミオ
Shirakami Fubuki / Ookami Mio
百鬼あやめ / 戌神ころね / 宝鐘マリン
Nakiri Ayame / Inugami Korone / Houshou Marine
Fashion Beat
Nya Hello! the beautiful days
刮目しちゃってくれ
Pay close attention to me!
Please call "Elite"
Please call me "Elite"!
(Funky dancin baby!)
Ah-ow!
Ow!
さぁ、待ったなしだ始めちゃえ
Now, no time to wait, let's get started!
今日もキメてくぜ　挑戦だ
I'll look cool today too, it's a challenge!
順番は厳禁？足踏みしてないで
Ordering is strictly prohibited? Don't stomp your feet,
一緒に「せーの！」でもっと前に行こう
Let's move forward together with a "One, two!"
ね？
Right?
さぁ、なんとかなっちゃう飛び込んで
Come on, it'll work out somehow, just dive in!
きっといつだって人生は冒険だ
Surely, life is always an adventure!
こんがらがったら待っとかないと
If you get tangled up, you have to wait,
道のりは困難だ
The path is difficult,
なんなんだ！
What the heck!
ずっとだ
It's always like this!
ダダダ (あっはぁ)
Da-da-da (A-ha!)
メソメソしちゃって
Sobbing and crying,
気持ちに「待った」しちゃって
putting a "hold" on your feelings.
あれ？一体全体どうしたん？
Huh? What in the world is wrong?
絶体絶命！
Desperate situation!
君たちには
For you guys,
涙は似合わないね！
tears don't suit you!
大胆不敵に飛び出そうぜ
Let's jump out fearlessly!
いざ、代わる代わるな心配も
Now, even with alternating worries,
重ねてって
pile them up,
挑戦だ Happy な phase 揃えて
It's a challenge! Align the happy phases,
君と笑い話にしよう
and let's make it a funny story with you.
うぇい！
Wei!
大々大々問題も吹き飛ばせ
Blow away even the biggest problems!
いつか、大大大団円の素敵な結末へ
Someday, to a wonderful ending of a grand finale!
Please me!!
さぁ、ついてきて？
Come on, follow me?
進め！前代未聞の New World
Advance! To an unprecedented New World!
Let's go!!
あながち間違ってる
Not necessarily wrong,
ま～た墓穴も掘ってる
digging my own grave again.
勉強 勉強
Study, study!
(はいはいはい、知ってます。)
(Yes yes yes, I know.)
(待って、なんか違ってる！)
(Wait, something's wrong!)
ぶっちゃけ有識者の
Honestly, to all the experts,
皆様に感謝してます
I am grateful to everyone.
Nice comment 待ってんぜ
Waiting for a Nice comment!
(あ～ね)
(Ah, I see.)
ウジウジしちゃって
Being hesitant,
心にロックしちゃって
locking up your heart.
ほら だんだんだん どうしたん？
Hey, gradually, what happened?
絶対絶命！
Desperate situation!
君たちには
For you guys,
笑顔が足りてないね！
you're missing smiles!
大大大々好きじゃ済まさない
Saying I love you lots isn't enough!
だから、大大大大 最高レベルに
So, at the highest level,
ガチの全力で
with serious full power,
Nya Hello!! 届けちゃうぜ
Nya Hello!! I'll deliver it!
ずっと大冒険しよう
Let's go on a big adventure forever!
Yeah!!
Nya Hello!! さぁ beautiful に
Nya Hello!! Come on, beautifully,
意気込んで 進め Freedom way
be enthusiastic and advance, Freedom way!
(wow wow)
乗り遅れんなよみんな
Don't miss the ride, everyone!
(wow wow)
声を聞かせてくれ Yeah!
Let me hear your voices, Yeah!
(wow wow)
歌おう声高らかに
Let's sing loudly!
Baby なんていうか
Baby, how should I put it,
あー、なんだかちょっと言い表せない
Ah, somehow I can't express it well.
一人ぼっちで見てた光景を
The scenery I watched all alone,
今はきっとあなたと冒険してる
now I'm surely adventuring through it with you.
大大大々... (大大大々)
Big big big big... (Big big big big)
大大大々好きじゃ収まらない
I love you big big big big isn't enough to contain it!
だから、大大大大 最高レベルに
So, at the highest level,
ガチの全力で
with serious full power,
Nya Hello!! 届けちゃうぜ
Nya Hello!! I'll deliver it!
ずっと大冒険しよう (Yeah!!)
Let's go on a big adventure forever! (Yeah!!)
大々大々問題も吹き飛ばせ
Blow away even the biggest problems!
いつか、大大大団円の素敵な結末へ
Someday, to a wonderful ending of a grand finale!
Please me!!
さぁ、ついてきて？
Come on, follow me?
進め！前代未聞の New World
Advance! To an unprecedented New World!
刮目しちゃってくれ
Pay close attention to me!
Please call "Elite"
Please call me "Elite"!
(Funky dancin baby!)
Ah-ow!
Ah!
とくべちゅ、して？
Give me a special kiss?
Oh baby "I love you" じゃ足りない
Oh baby, "I love you" isn't enough.
一番 大事がいい
I want to be your number one priority.
君が作るオリジナルの
Your original...
チューして
Kiss me.
眩しくて目が覚めて
Dazzling, I wake up.
Oh yeah!
愛おしく想ってよ
Think of me dearly.
Oh yeah!
眠り姫のように
Like Sleeping Beauty,
優しく口づけて
gently kiss me.
ゴミめいたこの世界
This trash-like world.
Oh yeah!
ピュアがある君がいる
There is you who has purity.
Oh yeah!
全てに触れずに
Without touching everything,
二人だけでいよう
let's be just the two of us.
私のこと独占して
Monopolize me.
君だけのモノになっていい
It's okay to become yours alone.
なんでもある日の
On any ordinary day,
「なんでもない」
"it's nothing."
気付いてね
Please notice.
Oh baby I love you じゃ足りない
Oh baby "I love you" isn't enough.
君の「特別」にして
Make me your "special one".
ねえもっと
Hey, more.
Give me a kiss もう私は
Give me a kiss, I am already
君でいっぱいよ
full of you.
ほどけないリボン結び
An untieable ribbon knot,
小指キュッて縛って
tie our pinkies tight.
そうよ 一生一緒がいいもん
That's right, I want to be together for a lifetime.
とくべチュが欲しい
I want a special kiss.
二人きり週末は
Just the two of us on the weekend,
Oh yeah!
奏でてよハーモニー
play a harmony.
Oh yeah!
流れ星見たら
If you see a shooting star,
私を想って欲しい
I want you to think of me.
甘々な君なのに
Even though you are so sweet,
Oh yeah!
広い街 吸い込まれ
swallowed up by the wide city,
Oh yeah!
戦う姿に
to your fighting figure,
大きい花丸だね
I give a big flower mark.
好きなところ、
Things I like,
優しいとこ。
your kindness.
嫌いなとこも、
Things I hate,
優しいとこ。
your kindness.
誰にもあげない
I won't give you to anyone.
私だけ 独り占め
I will monopolize you all for myself!
今までのお人とは
You don't need to be the same
同じはいらないんです
as the people from before.
ねえもっと Give me more love
Hey more, give me more love.
私のために
For my sake,
生きてほしいんです
I want you to live.
だからウサギと私は
So, rabbits and I,
寂しくさせないで
don't let us be lonely.
そんなんじゃ束縛じゃないわ
That's not being possessive.
苦しいのが好き
I like it painful.
ショートケーキ イチゴみたいに
Like a strawberry on a shortcake,
座ってもいい？
can I sit there?
赤く甘い恋だもん
It's a red and sweet love.
誰かにあげた
The "I love you"
「大好き」も
you gave to someone else,
返してもらって
take it back
全部私に
and give it all to me.
ちょーだい
Give it to me.
もっと
More.
ちょーだい
Give it to me.
もっと
More!
君は神様が作る
You are a miracle-like person
奇跡のようなヒト
created by God.
拗ねた顔も その寝顔も
Your sulking face, your sleeping face,
守ってあげるね
I will protect them all.
Yeah!
Oh baby I love you じゃ足りない
Oh baby "I love you" isn't enough.
君の「特別」にして
Make me your "special one".
ねえもっと
Hey, more.
Give me a kiss もう私は
Give me a kiss, I am already
君でいっぱいよ
full of you.
ほどけないリボン結び
An untieable ribbon knot,
小指キュッて縛って
tie our pinkies tight.
ねえ baby 最初で最後の
Hey baby, make it the first and last
とくべチュにしてね
special kiss, okay?
はーい！みんなにゃっはろー！
Yes! Hello everyone!
エリート巫女巫女…さくらみこ
Elite Shrine Maiden... Sakura Miko.
さくらみこ生誕祭2026 Fashion Beat に来てくれてどうもありがとうございまーす！
Thank you so much for coming to Sakura Miko Birthday Festival 2026 Fashion Beat!
今年でなんとみこちゃん… 18.8歳になりました！
Surprisingly, this year Miko-chan... has turned 18.8 years old!
たぶん18.8歳だよね
Probably 18.8 years old, right?
あの0.1でね 刻んでいく系のVtuberですから
Since I'm the type of VTuber who carves it out with that 0.1,
今年も18.8歳になっております
I have turned 18.8 years old this year too.
そしてそして 今回のライブのテーマは Fashion Beat にちなんでですね 「ファッション」となっております
And, and! The theme of this live concert is associated with "Fashion Beat", so it is "Fashion".
いろんなね演出が盛りだくさんなので ぜひ楽しんでください
Since there are plenty of various productions, please enjoy it.
じゃあねちょっとまあファッションちなんで みこちゃんもちょっとだけチェンジしちゃおうかな
Well then, since it's associated with fashion, maybe Miko-chan should change a little bit too.
はい上向いててください
Yes, please look up.
よいしょ
Heave-ho.
はい！
Yes!
ちゃらーん
Ta-da!
披露をしなかったこちらのキャストオフバージョン
This is the cast-off version I didn't show earlier,
になっております！こんな感じになってます
here it is! It looks like this.
かわいいでしょ？ちょっとセクシーですけどね
Cute, right? A little sexy though.
はーい！わーい！
Yeaaaah! Yaaay!
はい、次の曲はこれで披露しようと思っております
Okay, I plan to perform the next song in this outfit.
そして先ほどね、2曲ね、お送りしましたがどうでしたか？
Also, I just sent you two songs, how were they?
みこのオリ曲の「代代代代ファンタジスタ」と
Miko's original song 'Dai-Dai-Dai-Dai Fantasista' and...
そしてみこのね、大好きなアイドルさんの＝LOVEさんの「しゅきぴ」を
and my favorite idol =LOVE's 'Shukipi',
披露させていただきました
I was allowed to perform them!
とってもかわいかったでしょ？
It was really cute, right?
きゅるるん！きゅるるん！はーい
Kyururun! Kyururun! Okaaay.
あ、そうだ！ステージもね、ちょっと見せたいんですけど
Oh, right! I want to show you the stage too.
見てください！こちら！
Look at this! Over here!
今回のテーマにちなんで作っていただきました
They made it based on this year's theme.
ドレッサーとかね、めちゃくちゃね
The dresser and everything, it's totally...
なんかこう、みこが小人になったみたいな感じですけど
kinda like Miko has become a little dwarf or something,
ね、とってもかわいくなっております
hey, it's turned out really cute.
そして、こちらのね、トルソーね
And, on this torso here,
みこちゃんの歴代の衣装とかも少し飾ってあります
some of Miko-chan's past costumes are displayed.
全部じゃないんですけどね、はーい
Not all of them though, yup.
えーそして
Umm, and...
最後にですね
at the very end,
たくさんの告知があったりとか
there are lots of announcements,
新衣装のお披露目もございますので
and there's also the new outfit reveal,
ぜひ楽しんでもらえたらなと思っております
so I hope you enjoy it all!
では、早速ゲストパートいこうと思いますよ！
Well then, let's get right to the guest part!
よし、こうして
Alright, like this...
それではこの後も楽しんでね！
So, please enjoy what's coming next!
よし！
Okay!
ファッションモンスター
Fashion Monster
おもしろいって言いたいのに
I want to say it's interesting, but
言えないなんてつまらないでしょ
it's boring if I can't say it.
同じになっていい子ぶって
Being the same, acting like a good girl,
いたくないってキミもそうでしょ？
you don't want to be like that either, right?
誰かの
Someone's
ルールに
rules...
縛られたくはないの
I don't want to be bound by them.
わがまま
Selfish
ドキドキ
Heart-pounding
このままでいたい！
I want to stay like this!
ファッションモンスター
Fashion Monster
この狭い心の檻も
This narrow cage of the heart,
壊して自由になりたいの
I want to break it and be free.
ファッションモンスター
Fashion Monster
感覚を研ぎ澄ませて
Sharpen your senses,
キミのように
just like you.
吸い込まれてく
Being sucked in,
らせん模様みたいに
like a spiral pattern.
I wanna be free
ファッションモンスター
Fashion Monster
ただ普通に生きたいのに
I just want to live normally, but
変なことってつまらないでしょ
weird things are boring, right?
決めつけないでいい子でなんて
Don't judge me, saying 'be a good girl',
いたくないってキミもそうでしょ？
you don't want to stay like that either, right?
誰かの
Someone's
ルールに
rules,
縛られたくはないの
I don't want to be bound by them.
わがまま
Selfishness
ドキドキ
and excitement,
このままでいたい
I want to stay like this.
ファッションモンスター
Fashion Monster
鉄の首飾りをはずして
Take off this iron collar,
ただ自由に行きたいだけ
I just want to go freely.
ファッションモンスター
Fashion Monster
狭い心の檻も
Break the cage of a narrow mind,
壊して
destroy it,
自由になりたいの
I want to be free.
ファッションモンスター
Fashion Monster
咲き誇れ
Bloom proudly,
花よ舞い踊れ
dance, oh flowers!
明日を虹色に染め上げて
Dye tomorrow in the colors of the rainbow!
いくぞ！
Here we go!
夢色フェスティバル
Yumeiro Festival
はっ！
Ha!
ソイヤ！ソイヤ！
Soiya! Soiya!
あ どっこい！
A-dokkoi!
はっじまっるよー
It's starting!
今から歌うはウルトラスーパー
Singing now is the ultra-super
奇想天外お菓子の夢色リズムで
fantastic, sweet, dream-colored rhythm.
どうでもいい
I don't care about that!
大事なのは
What's important is
楽しむ心
a heart that enjoys itself.
準備はいいかな？
Are you ready?
遅れないでよ！
Don't be late!
あ！
Ah!
咲き誇れ君の
Bloom proudly,
ソイヤ！ソイヤ！
Soiya! Soiya!
そこから
from there!
心最高潮のフェスティバル
Heart's peak festival!
大事なのは信じる心
What's important is a believing heart.
君だけ聞こえるリズムに任せて
Trust the rhythm only you can hear.
あ！
Ah!
ワクワクしたいの！
I want to get excited!
ドキドキしたくない？
Don't you want to be thrilled?
いくぞ！
Let's go!
咲き誇れ君の
Bloom proudly,
ソイヤ！ソイヤ！
Soiya! Soiya!
そこから
from there!
ワクワク最高潮のフェスティバル
Excitement peak festival!
君色教えて
Tell me your color
そんな感じで
Just like that
夢のビートきざむらよ
Carve the beat of our dream
騒げー！
Make some noise!
咲き誇れ
Bloom in full glory
乙女のフェスティバル
A maiden's festival
笑顔満開
Smiles in full bloom
無限大
Infinite
It's Alright!
舞い踊れ
Dance and twirl
君色教えて
Tell me your color
そんな感じで
Just like that
夢のビート響かせてよ
Let the beat of the dream resound
だから止まらない
So I won't stop
まだ言わないで
Don't say it yet
呪文めいた
Like a spell,
その言葉
those words
”愛”なんて
Such things as "Love"
羽のように軽い
are light as a feather
囁いて
Whisper to me
パパより優しい
kinder than Papa
テノールで
in a tenor voice
奪う覚悟が
The resolve to steal,
あるのなら
if you possess it
百万の薔薇のベッドに
On a bed of a million roses
埋もれ見る
buried and dreaming
夢よりも
more fragrant
馨しく
than a dream
私は生きてるの
I am alive
どうせなら
If you're going to do it
醜いものが
where ugly things
はびこった
run rampant,
この世界
in this world
汚れずに
without being defiled
羽ばたいて
can we fly
行けるのか
and go on?
独り繭の中
Alone inside a cocoon
学び続けても
even if I keep learning
水晶の
the crystal
星空は
starry sky
遠すぎるの
is too far away
まだ触れないで
Don't touch me yet
その震える指先は
Those trembling fingertips
花盗人の
of a flower thief
甘い躊躇い
are a sweet hesitation
触れてもいい
You may touch
この深い胸の奥にまで
deep into this heart
届く自信が
The confidence to reach it,
あるのならば
if you have it
白馬の
A white horse
王子様なんて
prince or whatever
信じてる
it's not that
わけじゃない
I believe in him
ひび割れた
Cracked
ガラスケースに
in a glass case
飾られた
displayed
純潔は
purity is
滅びゆく
a perishing
天使たちの
angels'
心臓
heart
また明日も
Again tomorrow
目覚めるたびに
every time I wake up
百年の
A hundred years
刻を知る
of time I know
眠れない
Sleepless
魂の
soul's
茨姫
Thorn Princess
食い込む冠
The digging crown
一滴の血
One drop of blood
今が
That now is
真実と
the truth
思い知るの
I realize deeply
まだ行かないで
Don't go yet
月光の結界で
In the barrier of moonlight
過ちに
my mistake
気づいてしまいそう
I'm about to realize
安らかな
With just peaceful
温もりだけで
warmth
そうさこぼれてくる涙の意味さえわからない
That's right, I don't even understand the meaning of these overflowing tears.
もう言わないで呪文めいたその言葉
Don't say those spell-like words anymore.
「愛」なんて鎖のように重いだけ
"Love" is just heavy like a chain.
さあ泣いてパパより優しくしてあげる
Come on, cry, I'll treat you more gently than Papa.
どんなことば待っているならば
If you are waiting for some kind of words...
さあ誓ってよその震える唇で
Come on, swear it with those trembling lips.
蜜を摘む狩人のときめき
The excitement of a hunter picking honey.
獲物なった君になら誠意
If it's you who became the prey, I'll show sincerity...
この不甲斐なさの奥底を
The depths of this worthlessness...
射抜く指が
If the finger that shoots through...
あるのならば
...exists.
あなた捕まえたら
If I catch you...
決して逃がさないようにして
Make sure you never let me go.
恥ずかしいか青春は
Is youth embarrassing?
ぶつけたところから
From the place where we collided...
熟れていく果実のように
...like a ripening fruit.
僕らは些細なことで
We, over trivial things...
かさぶたになれずに
...without becoming a scab...
息せき切ってがむしゃらに
...out of breath, recklessly.
輝く一等星をめがけて
Aiming for the shining first-magnitude star...
手を伸ばしたよな
...we reached out our hands, didn't we?
天才されど大胆だ
A genius, yet bold.
うるさいこれが切り札だ
Shut up, this is my trump card.
泣き虫されど熱血だ
A crybaby, yet hot-blooded.
うるさいこれが持ち味だ
Shut up, this is my characteristic.
未開拓冒険地帯
Unexplored adventure zone.
好奇心旺盛時代
Era of brimming curiosity.
何が綺麗かはわかる
I know what is beautiful.
自分ならばある
If it's me, I have it.
恥ずかしいか青春は
Is youth embarrassing?
僕ら全力でやってんだ
We are doing it with all our might.
振りかざせ存在を
Brandish your existence.
あとどれくらい続いてくだろう
I wonder how much longer it will continue.
守り抜いた青春が
The youth we protected to the end...
何よりの贅沢だ
...is the greatest luxury of all.
きっといつか
Surely someday...
焦がれ思い返す
...we will yearn and look back.
名前のない関係を
This nameless relationship...
素敵でない感情を
...these not-so-wonderful emotions...
何気ない今日を忘れないでね
...don't forget this ordinary day, okay?
いずれは行こうぜ
Let's go there someday,
越えられない今日を
spending this unsurpassable day
過ごしていたいよ
that I want to keep living in.
今しかできないことがある
There are things we can only do now.
今しかできない恋がある
There is love we can only find now.
今しかできないから 僕らに
Because we can only do it now, for us...
託された時間が惜しい
the time entrusted to us is so precious.
今しか見られない
We can only see it now—
君の笑顔も
your smile,
君の涙も
your tears,
君の全てをも
and your everything.
大人になっていく
We are growing up.
有限だから最高だ
It's the best because it's finite.
恥ずかしいか 青春は
Is youth embarrassing?
馬鹿らしいか 真剣は
Is seriousness foolish?
僕ら全力でやってんだ
We are doing this with all our might!
振りかざせ 存在を
Brandish your existence,
かき乱せ 心臓を
stir up your heart,
胸に刻めば
if you carve it into your chest,
続いてくだろう
it will surely continue on.
守り抜いた青春が
The youth we protected to the end
何よりもの贅沢だ
is a luxury greater than anything.
きっといつか
Surely someday,
焦がれ思い返す
we will yearn and look back
名前のない関係を
on this nameless relationship,
素敵じゃない感情を
on these unpolished emotions.
何気ない今日を忘れないでね
Don't forget this ordinary day.
越えられない今日を
This unsurpassable day—
忘れないでね
don't ever forget it.
アイドルだから
Because I am an idol,
挑み続けるんだ
I will keep challenging myself.
君と夢見るんだ
I will dream with you.
不器用で悪いか
Is it bad to be clumsy?
咲き誇るよ
I will bloom proudly!
初のイベント 需要なしで
First event, zero demand...
そんな私が夢を見ました
Someone like me dreamed a dream.
アイドルという生き方
The way of life called "Idol"—
憧れて
I yearned for it.
無責任とか 笑顔落ちたとか
Calling me irresponsible, or saying my smile faded...
そんな私を見てくれる君
You, who still watches someone like me,
好きのとこはどこですか？
what is the part that you like?
ね
Hey...
我がままを許して
forgive my selfishness.
ステージ景色 涙滲んで
The stage scenery is blurred by tears,
それでも絶対負けたくない
but even so, I absolutely won't lose!
桜にメッセージ乗せて届け
Deliver this message on the cherry blossoms,
愛で溢れますように
so that it overflows with love!
アイドルだから
Because I am an idol,
挑み続けるんだ
I will keep challenging myself.
君と夢見るんだ
I will dream with you.
不器用で悪いか
Is it bad to be clumsy?
咲き誇れ
Bloom proudly!
妄想だけじゃ終わらせない
I won't let it end as just a delusion.
私が咲く
I will bloom
桜色ね
in cherry blossom colors!
磨いたスキル
My polished skills
実力発揮
on full display.
楽しめる暇 増えてきたかも
The time I can enjoy might have increased.
アイドルとして生きてる
I'm living as an idol
君のおかげ
thanks to you.
アホ毛はキュート
My ahoge is cute,
ガチ恋はルート？
is true love the route?
そんな私についてきてよね
So follow someone like me, okay?
ドジなとこも許されて
Forgiven even for my clumsiness—
最強じゃん
isn't that the strongest?
みこちー！
Mikochi!
痛いの痛いの飛んでけって飲み込んで
Swallowing down the pain,
笑顔で笑顔 増やしたいな
I want to multiply smiles with smiles.
桜前線が
The cherry blossom front
君の街に
is heading to your town
春を届けるように
to deliver the spring.
アイドルだけは
Being an idol is the one thing
譲りたくないんだ
I don't want to give up.
君に見てたいんだ
I want you to watch.
いつも偉い 友よ
To my friends who are always elite...
駆け抜けろ 最高景色見せてあげる
Run through! I'll show you the best scenery.
信じていいよ
You can believe in me.
桜をさ
The cherry blossoms...
みんなで咲かそう
let's make them bloom together!
満開のピンクで 世界染めてしまえ
Dye the world in full-bloom pink!
ああ この涙はね
Ah, these tears...
悲しい方じゃないから
they aren't the sad kind,
安心して
so don't worry.
綺麗だね
It's beautiful, isn't it?
私の感情に追いついてくれてありがとう
Thank you for keeping up with my feelings.
みんな大好きだよ！
I love you all!
アイドルだから
Because I am an idol.
誓い続けるんだ 痛み続けるんだ
I'll keep vowing, I'll keep hurting
君と夢見るんだ
I'll dream with you
不器用でも悪いか 咲き誇れ
Is it wrong to be clumsy? Bloom proudly
みんな、ありがとー！
Everyone, thank you!
ありがとー！
Thank you!
ありがとね。
Thanks, you know.
ちゅ！
Mwah!
ありがとー！
Thank you!
ちゅっ！
Mwah!
ありがとー！
Thank you!
お祝いしてくれてありがとね！
Thank you for celebrating with me!
楽しんでる？
Are you having fun?
ありがとー！
Thank you!
ありがと！
Thanks!
うーん、まっ！
Mwah!
見てるよー！
I see you!
みんな見てるよー！
I see everyone!
よーし！
Alright!
ということで！
So with that said!
ライブ、まだまだ盛り上がる準備できてますかー！？
Are you ready to get even more hyped for the live concert!?
みんな！
Everyone!
まだまだ見逃さないでね！
Don't look away yet, okay!
よーし！
Alright!
次の曲いきます！
I'm heading to the next song!
Now I'm ready, I'm ready to go
花が咲く時が来たんだ
The time for the flowers to bloom has come
Are you ready? 分かるでしょ
Are you ready? You know it, right
やってみせる Make it through
I'll show you I can do it, Make it through
Hold on
飛んだ
Flew past
Confusion 無視した
Ignored the confusion
時は過ぎちゃうから
Because time will just pass by
今すぐに Let's work it out
Right now, Let's work it out
Move on
目を
Eyes
背けやしないんだ
I won't turn them away
自分で Make up veil
I'll Make up veil myself
作る正解は
The correct answer I create is
I just wanna, just wanna find somebody
私よりも強気な敵か？
Is it an enemy tougher than me?
Oh... Watch me now, make you high
準備体操済んでんだ
The warm-up exercises are done
No longer back down, so now let's start the war!
I'm fighting my way
夢の未来へ
Towards the dream future
信じて進むだけ
Just believe and move forward
誰にも絶対
To absolutely no one
負ける気なんかない
I have no intention of losing
君に見せたいの
I want to show you
彼方の景色を
The scenery beyond
Only lonely
It's all right
全部連れて
Taking it all with me
もっと刺激が知りたい
I want to know more stimulation
もう止まれないやいや
I can't stop anymore, no no
I'll be the light
That shines on the way
Hey!
時また
Time again
一回一秒まで Make it
Every single second, Make it
ちょっと待ったなんか
Wait a sec, something
破壊なみこも超だな
Destructive Miko is also super, huh
ねえ、今日と明日がまた違うわけではないな
Hey, it's not like today and tomorrow are different again
Challenging myself just wanna keep changing
こんなファンタジスタ
Such a fantasista
ハマったなもっともっと
You're hooked, more and more
欲しくなっちゃうよ
You'll start wanting it
No
恐れはしないんだ
I'm not afraid
君となら行けると気づいたから
Because I realized I can go if I'm with you
Come join us
Home in
聞こえてくるから
Because I can hear it coming
Yeah, 私の名を呼ぶ方へ
Yeah, towards where you call my name
I'm fighting my way
夢の未来へ
Towards the dream future
信じて進むだけ
Just believe and move forward
誰にも絶対
To absolutely no one
負ける気なんかない
I have no intention of losing
君に見せたいの
I want to show you
彼方の景色を
The scenery beyond
胸を打って
Strike your chest
夜を抜いて
Pass through the night
大空の彼方に跨った
Straddling the beyond of the vast sky
Ah Uh Wah
一つも無駄はないさ
Not a single thing is wasted
ここに立って
Standing here
変えてくから
I'll keep changing it
Killer Killer
刺激と弾けた
Burst with stimulation
Oh call me now
Oh, パシめした
Oh, punished it
強がってくよ Make you high
I'll keep acting tough, Make you high
後悔はさせない Watch me work
I won't let you regret it, Watch me work
転んだ分だけ Rise, so now let's start the war
Rise as much as I fell, so now let's start the war
I'm fighting with myself
負けなんてないさ
There's no such thing as defeat
ややや、しゃぶけてたって
Ya ya ya, even if I was pouting
立ち上がる気持ち分
For every feeling of standing up
一回私に勝ってない
You haven't beaten me once
君がいれば
If you are here
何度も立ち上がるわ
I'll stand up again and again
愛は歌って
Singing love
想い全て
All my feelings
逃げ場はない間違いない
There's no escape, no mistake
まだ終わらないやいや
It's not over yet, no no
I need you to stay
You make me feel okay, hey!
ひたすら Shine
Just intensely Shine
行こう空の上まで
Let's go, above the sky
Ahhh
ooh
uh
唸るぜ
It makes me growl,
血泥ついたって
even covered in muddy blood,
守りたい
I want to protect it.
革命道中だって
Even in the midst of a revolution,
君に夢中
I'm obsessed with you.
暗闇染み込む世界で
In a world soaked in darkness,
見つけた
I found it,
センチメンタルな恋
a sentimental love.
甘くぬかるんだ眼差し
A sweet, quagmire-like gaze,
変に色気あるから困る
it's troubling because it's strangely sexy.
手をつなぐ勇気出したくて
Wanting to summon the courage to hold hands,
身の程弁えてちゃ出来ないね
I can't do it if I just know my place.
くだらない能書きこねるの勘弁
Spare me the worthless lectures,
滴り落ちる秘密
dripping secrets.
締めやかに高鳴る鼓動
A heartbeat throbbing quietly.
ダメダメ
No, no,
待て待て
wait, wait.
呪いも病も抱きしめたい
I want to embrace even curses and sickness.
ここらで暴れちゃってもいいかな
Is it okay if I go wild around here?
嗚呼
Ah!
唸るぜ
It makes me growl,
血泥ついたって
even covered in muddy blood,
守りたい
I want to protect it.
革命道中だって
Even in the midst of a revolution,
君に夢中
I'm obsessed with you.
暗闇染み込む世界で
In a world soaked in darkness,
見つけた
I found it,
センチメンタルな恋
a sentimental love.
ダメダメ
No, no.
待て待て
Wait, wait.
なりふり構わず側にいたい
I want to be by your side without caring how it looks.
不器用な君にも期待しちゃうの
I end up expecting things even from clumsy you.
強がり突き抜けそうな君に
To you, who seems about to break through your bravado,
本音冷めかけて近づいてもいい？
can I get close even if my true feelings are cooling down?
身を任せたからって
Just because I gave myself to you,
全て失ってもいい
I don't mind losing everything.
締めやかに高鳴る鼓動
A heartbeat throbbing quietly.
ダメダメ
No, no,
待て待て
wait, wait.
呪いも病も抱きしめたい
I want to embrace even curses and sickness.
ここらで暴れちゃってもいいかな
Is it okay if I go wild around here?
嗚呼
Ah!
のっけるぜ
I'll ride it,
絶句しちゃうまで
until you're left speechless,
離れない
I won't let go.
革命道中だって
Even in the midst of a revolution,
君に夢中
I'm obsessed with you.
さすらう旅の狭間で
In the rifts of a wandering journey,
見つけた
I found it,
センチメンタルな恋
a sentimental love.
突き進むなら二人で
If we're charging forward, let's do it together.
革命道中だって
Even in the midst of a revolution,
夢に熱中
obsessed with the dream.
ダメダメ
No, no,
待て待て
wait, wait.
呪いも病も抱きしめたい
I want to embrace even curses and sickness.
ここらで暴れちゃってもいいよね
It's fine if I go wild around here, right?
怖くない
I'm not scared.
唸るぜ
It makes me growl,
血泥ついたって
even covered in muddy blood,
守りたい
I want to protect it.
革命道中だって
Even in the midst of a revolution,
君に夢中
I'm obsessed with you.
暗闇染み込む世界で
In a world soaked in darkness,
見つけた
I found it,
センチメンタルな恋
a sentimental love.
飛んで火に入る夏の虫
Like moths flying into the summer fire.
同じ穴の狢玩具
Birds of a feather, just toys.
一世一代の大仕事
A once-in-a-lifetime big job.
伸るか反るかの大博打
A sink-or-swim huge gamble.
自問自答
Self-questioning.
勝つか負けるか
Win or lose?
0か100か
0 or 100?
ってないわ
There is no...
幕開けるわ
The curtain rises.
Gotcha gotcha してる
It's all messy,
lucky money どっちも無理
lucky money, neither is possible.
Sugar Sugar
行けるか何か自分次第だ
Can you go? It's all up to you.
余裕で
With ease,
右左
left and right,
Red or Green
そこ退け
Step aside,
step aside!
Queenのお出ましだ
The Queen has arrived.
Stay
かたくなな変調子
Stubborn irregular meter.
Head shot
One two three One two three One two three
Sit down, Sit down
はーもうフリーズ決めたや
Hah, I already decided to freeze.
投げるのはサイコロそっちか？
Are you the one rolling the dice?
そんな小さい指図じゃ測れない
Can't measure with such small orders.
でしょうそれじゃ Say Goodbye や
Right? Then say goodbye.
あっちこっちそっちどっちなしなし yam yam
Here, there, that way, which way, none, none, yum yum.
道なき道を yam yam yam
Yum yum yum on the pathless path.
空回りそうでもまだ止めないで
Seems like I'm spinning in circles, but don't stop yet.
頭りそう 声枯れしょめしょめに
Going to hard head, voice withering into blah blah.
Get out way
Way... Yeah...
アンタここマネ
You go up to here.
後ろだけ見とけ
Just watch my back.
ガッチリして Lucky money
Solidly Lucky money.
どっちも無理 自我自我
Both are impossible, ego ego.
行けるか否か自分次第だな
Whether I can go or not is up to me.
余裕で振り切る全力で Yeah yeah yeah yeah
Shaking it off with ease, with all my power.
存在だけですぐの out
Just by existing, it's an immediate out.
まっさらのあたしだ
It's brand new me.
Stayもいいクラクラ平常心
Stay is fine too, dizzy composure.
ねぇ Play boy 行け Don't get in my way
Hey Play boy, go, Don't get in my way.
邪魔黙って
You're in the way, shut up.
One two three...
見つかんない Bye bye One two three...
Can't find it, Bye bye One two three...
Sit down, Sit down
特報！
NEWS FLASH!
フルアニメーションMV
FULL ANIMATION MV
配信後プレミア公開！
PREMIERE RELEASE AFTER STREAM!
MV公開に先駆けて
AHEAD OF THE MV RELEASE
ARE YOU READY?
ファッションビート
Fashion Beat
痛くて目を塞いでも
Even if it hurts and I close my eyes,
聞こえちゃう不安症
I can still hear it, anxiety disorder.
悩んでも変わらないから
Because worrying won't change anything,
なんだかんだやるしかないか
I guess I just have to do it somehow.
壊れるならいっそ直しやすいように
If it's going to break, let it break so it's easier to fix.
どんな形目指せるかな
What kind of shape can I aim for?
助走なしのジャンプ見物して dive
Jump without a run-up, watch and dive.
今日のあたし褒めてあげたいじゃんか
I want to praise the me of today.
息したい
I want to breathe.
もっと響きたいねぇ
I want to resonate more, hey.
あたし以上が見れるかも
Maybe I can see something beyond myself.
妄想止まんないや
Delusions won't stop.
ファッションビート吐いてちゃう夢に
Fashion beat, vomiting into the dream.
昔にあったぞなんて吐きやしないな
I won't say things like 'it was there in the past'.
叶えるのはあたし自身か
Is the one granting it myself?
それとも誰かにお任せ？
Or leaving it to someone else?
ただただ自分に勝ちたい
I just, just want to beat myself.
ニューファッションビート愛を食ら
New Fashion beat, eat love.
負けるなんてごめんだ味がしないな
Sorry but losing has no flavor.
何度でも灰になる進化
Evolution that turns to ash again and again.
生まれ変わるバカ的進化
Reborn, idiotic evolution.
まだまだ腐ってあげないそんな
I won't rot just yet, no way.
チクチク刺してくるのは
What keeps stinging me pricklingly,
飽き飽きしてるわ
I'm sick and tired of it.
ごめんウザい言葉遊びは
Sorry, annoying wordplay,
どこかちゃんとしまっておいて
Put it away somewhere properly.
私こそがライバル
I am the rival.
炙り出しの開花
Blooming that smokes it out.
どうしたらいいわかってるのに
Even though I know what I should do.
助走なしのジャンプ見物して dive
Jump without a run-up, watch and dive.
今日のあたし出来る気しないなって
Saying 'I don't feel like I can do it today'.
気にしないなんて無理じゃない？
Isn't it impossible to not care?
ねぇあたし以外と比べても
Hey, even if you compare me to others,
クソつまんないじゃんか
It's f*cking boring.
腐ってあげないそんな
I won't let it rot, no way
止まれない
Can't stop
誰かじゃないあたし自身だ
It's not someone else, it's me
生まれ変わる
Reborn
まだ
Not yet
散ってあげないそんな
I won't scatter, no way
みんなライブ見てくれてありがとう！
Thanks everyone for watching the live!
これからは告知のお時間です
Now it's time for announcements.
まずはこちら！
First up is this!
さくらみこ誕生日記念2026
Sakura Miko Birthday Celebration 2026
記念グッズです！
Commemorative goods!
まずは一つ目こちら、タダーン！
First one here, ta-da!
アクリルパネル！
Acrylic Panel!
イラストレーターはおるだん先生に描き下ろしていただきました
Illustrated by Ordan-sensei.
テーマは電脳世界のミコ！
The theme is Cyber World Miko!
新衣装のみこを描き下ろしてもらいました
He drew Miko in her new outfit.
オーロラ加工でキラキラのアクリルパネルとなっております
It's a sparkling acrylic panel with aurora processing.
めっちゃ可愛い
So cute.
続いてはこちら
Next is this.
スマホスタンドフィギュアです！
Smartphone Stand Figure!
スマホが立てかけられるスタンド、そして新衣装のみこのフィギュア
A stand to prop up your phone, and a figure of Miko in her new outfit.
めちゃくちゃ可愛くないですか？
Isn't it super cute?
これ沢山こだわったのでね
We put a lot of detail into this,
ぜひこのスタンドにスマホを立てかけて配信見てくれたら嬉しいです
so I'd be happy if you used it to watch streams.
続いてはこちら
Next is this.
ガジェットケース！
Gadget Case!
新衣装にちなんで、ちょっとこういうあんまり出さないグッズも考えてみました
Inspired by the new outfit, I thought of a good we don't usually release.
ケーブルとかモバイルバッテリーなど、小物を収納できるケースとなっております
It's a case to store small items like cables and mobile batteries.
ソフトな素材になってるよ
It's made of soft material.
最後はこちら
Lastly, this.
ナイロンジャケット！
Nylon Jacket!
新衣装をモチーフにしたナイロンジャケットとなっております
This nylon jacket is based on the new outfit.
ちょっとかっこいめのデザインなので
It's a bit of a cool design,
みんな一緒にお揃いになってくれたら嬉しいです
so I'd be happy if everyone matched with me.
そしてフルセット購入特典はこちら
And here is the full set purchase bonus.
さくらみこ直筆サイン＆箔押し複製メッセージ入り、おるだん描き下ろしポストカードとなっております
Ordan-sensei illustrated postcard with Miko's hand-signed autograph and foil-stamped message.
まあちょっと数量限定にはなるんですが
Well, it is limited in quantity,
みんなお早めによろしくお願いします
so please order early, everyone!
そして通常版は、さくらみこ箔押し複製サイン＆メッセージ入りのポストカードとなっております
And the regular version is a postcard with Miko's foil-stamped signature and message.
みんな、ぜひね沢山手に入れてくれると嬉しいです
I'd be happy if you all got lots of them.
よろしくお願いします
Please check it out!
そして告知二つ目はこちら！
And the second announcement is this!
なんと！さくらみこ、学研さんの参考書シリーズが発売決定になりました！
Believe it or not! Sakura Miko x Gakken Reference Book Series release has been decided!
ホロライブStudyBook、さくらみこでもわかるシリーズとなっております
Hololive Study Book: 'Even Sakura Miko Can Understand' Series.
中学漢字＋語彙、中学数学、中学英単語、中学地理＋都道府県の4冊が発売決定です！
Four books: JH Kanji+Vocab, Math, English Words, and Geography+Prefectures!
そして初回限定の愛蔵版も発売予定となっております
And a First Press Limited Collector's Edition is also planned.
4月下旬頃より予約開始なので、引き続き続報チェックしてね
Pre-orders start around late April, so keep checking for updates.
みこでもわかるシリーズ
'Even Miko Can Understand' Series...
うん、みんな説得力があると思うよね
Yeah, I think you all find that convincing, right?
次！三つ目はこちら！
Next! Third one is this!
さくらみこ×フレーベル館 初の絵本
Sakura Miko x Froebel-kan, First Picture Book
「みこぴーと おおきな さくらのき」が、本日より発売です！
'Mikopi and the Big Cherry Tree' is on sale starting today!
もう買ってくれた人もいるかな？
Maybe some of you bought it already?
いつも支えてくれているみこぴーを題材に、夢だった絵本を作ることができました
I was able to make my dream picture book featuring the Mikopis who always support me.
全国の書店やローソンさんで購入可能なので
Available at bookstores nationwide and Lawson,
ぜひぜひみんな手に取ってください、よろしくお願いします！
so please pick one up, everyone! Thanks!
頑張りました！
I did my best!
続いてもこちら大発表！
Continuing with a big announcement here!
四つ目はこちら！
Fourth one is this!
さくらみこフィギュア化が決定しました！
Sakura Miko figure production decided!
おるだん先生監修にて、みこの夢だった...
Supervised by Ordan-sensei, Miko's dream...
等身大フィギュアがついに完成です！
The life-size figure is finally complete!
やったー！
Yay!
スケールフィギュアも同時に予約販売が決まりました
Pre-orders for the scale figure have also been decided.
明日3月6日から予約開始です
Pre-orders start tomorrow, March 6th.
エキスポのDesign COCOさんブースで展示されるので
It will be displayed at the Design COCO booth at the Expo,
みんな見に来てね、たくさん写真撮ってね！
so come see it and take lots of photos!
またこの等身大フィギュアも展示される
Also, this life-size figure will be displayed at...
京都IP書店×さくらみこのポップアップショップも開催決定となりました！
Kyoto IP Bookstore x Sakura Miko Pop Up Shop has been decided!
すごい！
Amazing!
リニューアルオープンした京都 蔦屋書店IP書店さんで、4月28日から開催です
Held at the renewed Kyoto Tsutaya IP Bookstore starting April 28th.
オリジナルグッズの発売や、ノベルティのコラボも行われるので
There will be original goods and novelty collaborations,
皆さん楽しみにしてください
so please look forward to it.
盛りだくさんだー！
So much stuff!
そしてまだございます
And there is still more.
続いてはこちら
Next is this.
PCケース発売決定！
PC Case release decided!
キーキャップとデスクマットのセットもございます
There is also a keycap and desk mat set available.
先行予約リリースのメール通知や詳細については hyte.co/miko を見てみてください
For pre-order release notifications and details, please check hyte.co/miko.
楽しみにしててねー！
Please look forward to it!
そして！
And then!
今年もさくらみこ×鳴門鯛焼本舗さんのコラボが実施中です！
The Sakura Miko x Naruto Taiyaki Honpo collab is happening again this year!
今年でなんと4回目です
This is already the 4th time!
ありがとうございます
Thank you very much.
3月31日までなのでみんな是非食べに行ってください
It's until March 31st, so everyone please go eat some.
続いて
Next up,
新曲「Fashion Beat」本日0時よりリリースです
New song 'Fashion Beat' released today at 0:00.
MVはこの後プレミア公開！
The MV will premiere right after this!
みんな見てねー
Everyone watch it okay?
とっても豪華なアニメMVとなっております
It has become a very gorgeous anime MV.
よろしくお願いします
Please check it out.
はい そしてこちら！
Okay, and this!
明日からホロライブエキスポ アンド 7thフェス開催でーす！
From tomorrow, Hololive Expo and 7th Fes will be held!
3日間の開催ですよ すごーい
It's a 3-day event! Amazing!
みこはですね 7thフェスではDay2のステージ2に参加します
As for Miko, I will participate in Stage 2 on Day 2 of the 7th Fes.
みんな見に来てねー
Everyone come watch!
この後はメンバー限定の撮影会もあるので
After this, there is also a member-only photo session,
みんな「35P」になってねー
so everyone please become a '35P' (Miko-P)!
ということで 告知が盛り盛りの森になりましたが
So, the announcements became a forest of plenty,
みんなついてこれたかな？
Could everyone keep up?
みここれからも頑張るので
Miko will continue to do her best,
よろしくお願いします
so please support me.
誕生日祝ってくれてありがとう！
Thank you for celebrating my birthday!
おつみこー！
Otsu-Miko!
出演: さくらみこ / 戌神ころね / 35P / 百鬼あやめ / 白上フブキ / 大空スバル / 大神ミオ / 宝鐘マリン / 常闇トワ
Cast: Sakura Miko / Inugami Korone / 35P / Nakiri Ayame / Shirakami Fubuki / Oozora Subaru / Ookami Mio / Houshou Marine / Tokoyami Towa
サムネイル: 憂姫はぐれ / もちぷよ
Thumbnail: Yuuki Hagure / Mochipuyo
司会: sakuⓇ
MC: sakuⓇ
映像制作: [OP映像] 紺屋本舗 (スタジオメイピー)
Video Production: [OP Video] Kouya Honpo (Studio Meipy)
スタジオメイピー: Kanauru / brat
Studio Meipy: Kanauru / brat
[OP楽曲アレンジ制作] コルソン
[OP Song Arrangement] Corson
[グッズ紹介映像] 堕落びて
[Merch Intro Video] Daraku Bite
[VJ/OL] 紺屋本舗 / てうつ藩 / D2taiL (スタジオメイピー) / たんしお / 生命ぜろ
[VJ/OL] Kouya Honpo / Teutsuhan / D2taiL (Studio Meipy) / Tanshio / Seimeizero
振付: [振付] FreeM / 足太ぺんた / 槙田紗子
Choreography: [Choreography] FreeM / Ashibuto Penta / Makita Sako
Music: [合同会社 VESSEL LIFE]
Music: [VESSEL LIFE LLC]
[トライフロンティア合同会社] クックルP / すくろーす / 宮内翔太
[Tri-Frontier LLC] Kukkuru P / Sucrose / Miyauchi Shota
[株式会社サウンド・シティ] 小林紗彩 / 吉田美千加 / 柏倉吉紀 / 堀口彩花
[Sound City Inc.] Kobayashi Saaya / Yoshida Michika / Kashiwagura Yoshiki / Horiguchi Ayaka
SPECIAL THANKS: 35P / COVER Corp. STUDIO
誕生記念フルセット / 箔押し複製サイン入り
Birthday Commemorative Full Set / with Foil Stamped Reproduction Signature
hololive production OFFICIAL SHOPにて販売 / 受注期間: 2026年3/5(木)〜4/6(月) 18:00まで
On sale at hololive production OFFICIAL SHOP / Order period: March 5th (Thu) - April 6th (Mon) 2026, 18:00